Sufyan Saleem

Address: Phase 6, Sector F8, Street 4, House 425, Hayatabad, Peshawar

Email: sufyansalim94@gmail.com Mobile: +923139243550

OBJECTIVE

I am a 24 years old Software Engineer who loves to play with different technologies. I am looking forward for a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WORK EXPERIENCE		
<u>Linknbit</u>	Software Engineer	Islamabad Pakistan
Jan 2019 – present	Working for Software Development and IT Solo Agency. My main roles includes developing Wo Web Applications and Hybrid Mobile Application	utions ebsites,
Jan 2019 – present	Global Aviation System	I am working on parts of backend Node JS, Express, Swagger, Sequelize cli & Azure SQL
	 Dynasty Unleashed Models Modeling agency App for Fashion designers and marketers Users can register, create profile, add people and hire models at will 	Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native & part of Deployment to Firebase & Google Play
	 Ecommerce Mobile App. User can register, select products, add products to cart. User add products to wish list and checkout. Website Project was abandoned on last stage before deployment due to funds not provided. 	React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Node JS, Rest API, Word Press API, Woo Commerce API, Native Base
	 Yogurt App Step-by-step guide to home crafted authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate. 	Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo, Native Base
	<u>SmartsAid</u>	React/React-Native, Expo,

NGO App for refuges

Redux, Firebase, Rest API,

React Native Elements

2018 - FYP Currency Recognition & Conversion Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB Developed an app where users can scan currency note and it will tell which currency it is and how much is it and also show the exchange rate in USD. 2014 - 2018 Content Management Systems Java, C#, MSSQL Gym - Point of Sale PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL 2010 RuneScape RPG Java Created bot script for the game called runescape. The bot played the game for you. Portfolio Projects DevCamper API NodeJS, Express, Mongoose, Bootcamps API MongoDB, Node mailer, One can register as a User or Security for XSS and NOSQL Publisher and login also. Injection Publisher can create Bootcamps. Admin and Publisher can add courses and perform various CRUD operations. Users can comment on Bootcamps and update their profile, add picture

DevConnector

Social Media for developers where users register.

and reset password.

 Create profile, create posts, add comments and like and unlike them. React, Redux, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, NodeJS, Heroku, Context API

EDUCATION

Internet of things and Al Specialist Course

PIAIC, Islamabad (2019 - present)

BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78

Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

F.Sc - Pre-Engineering, grade B

ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

10 Matric, grade A

Racines School System, Peshawar (2010 – 2012)

SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE

Specialities

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

Social Links









Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo JS, Node JS, Express Mongoose, Sequelize Firebase, Mongo DB HTML, CSS, Bootstrap Git, Heroku Rust

Word press, Android Studio, Adobe PS

LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES

Languages

English Urdu Pashto

Hobbies

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking, Bodybuilding, Learning new Technologies